{"test_questions": [[{"question": "For quality control of Portland cement, the test essentially done is", "opta": "setting time", "optb": "soundness", "optc": "tensile strength", "optd": "consistency", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If 1500 g of water is required to have a cement paste 1875 g of normal consistency, the percentage of water is,", "opta": "20%", "optb": "25%", "optc": "30%", "optd": "35%", "opte": "40%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Under normal conditions using an ordinary cement, the period of removal of the form work, is :", "opta": "7 days for beam soffits", "optb": "14 days for bottom slabs of spans 4.6 m and more", "optc": "21 days for bottom beams over 6 m spans", "optd": "2 days for vertical sides of columns", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Wp and Wf are the weights of a cylinder containing partially compacted and fully compacted concrete. If the compaction factor  is 0.95, the workability of concrete is", "opta": "extremely low", "optb": "very low", "optc": "low", "optd": "high", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For given water content, workability decreases if the concrete aggregates contain an excess of", "opta": "thin particles", "optb": "flat particles", "optc": "elongated particles", "optd": "flaky paticles", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "M10 grade of concrete approximates", "opta": "1 : 3 : 6 mix", "optb": "1 : 1 : 2 mix", "optc": "1 : 2 : 4 mix", "optd": "1 : 1.5 : 3 mix", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For ensuring quality of concrete, use", "opta": "single sized aggegates", "optb": "two sized aggregate", "optc": "graded aggregates", "optd": "coarse aggregates.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "According to I.S. : 456, the number of grades of concrete mixes, is", "opta": "3", "optb": "4", "optc": "5", "optd": "6", "opte": "7", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The mixture of different ingredients of cement, is burnt at", "opta": "1000\u00b0C", "optb": "1200\u00b0C", "optc": "1400\u00b0C", "optd": "1600\u00b0C", "opte": "1800\u00b0C", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The risk of segregation is more for", "opta": "wetter mix", "optb": "larger proportion of maximum size aggregate", "optc": "coarser grading", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "After casting, an ordinary cement concrete on drying", "opta": "expands", "optb": "mix", "optc": "shrinks", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hydration of cement is due to chemical action of water with", "opta": "Tricalcium silicate and dicalcium silicate", "optb": "Dicalcium silicate and tricalcium aluminate", "optc": "Tricalcium aluminate and tricalcium alumino ferrite", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To obtain cement dry powder, lime stones and shales or their slurry, is burnt in a rotary kiln at a temperature between", "opta": "1100\u00b0 and 1200\u00b0C", "optb": "1200\u00b0 and 1300\u00b0C", "optc": "1300\u00b0 and 1400\u00b0C", "optd": "1400\u00b0 and 1500\u00b0C", "opte": "1500\u00b0 and 1600\u00b0C", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Permissible compressive strength of M 300 concrete grade is", "opta": "100 kg/cm2", "optb": "150 kg/cm2", "optc": "200 kg/cm2", "optd": "250 kg/cm2", "opte": "300 kg/cm2", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The standard sand now a days used in India, is obtained from", "opta": "Jaipur (Rajasthan)", "optb": "Jullundur (Punjab)", "optc": "Hyderabad (Andhra Pradesh)", "optd": "Ennore (Madras)", "opte": "Cuttuck (Orissa).", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum amount of dust which may be permitted in aggregates is", "opta": "5% of the total aggregates for low workability with a coarse grading", "optb": "10% of the total aggregates for low workability with a fine grading", "optc": "20% of the total aggregates for a mix having high workability with fine grading", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Proper proportioning of concrete, ensures", "opta": "desired strength and workability", "optb": "desired durability", "optc": "water tightness of the structure", "optd": "resistance to water", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bulk density of aggregates does not depend upon :", "opta": "size and shape of aggregates", "optb": "specific gravity of aggregates", "optc": "grading of aggregates", "optd": "size and shape of the container", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Curing", "opta": "reduces the shrinkage of concrete", "optb": "preserves the properties of concrete", "optc": "prevents the loss of water by evaporation", "optd": "all of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "While compacting the concrete by a mechanical vibrator, the slump should not exceed", "opta": "2.5 cm", "optb": "5.0 cm", "optc": "7.5 cm", "optd": "10 cm", "opte": "15 cm", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Construction joints are provided", "opta": "where B.M. and S.F. are small", "optb": "where the member is supported by other member", "optc": "at 18 m apart in huge structures", "optd": "in concrete wall at sill level of windows", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An aggregate is said to be flaky if its least dimension is less than", "opta": "1/5th of mean dimension", "optb": "2/5th of mean dimension", "optc": "3/5th of mean dimension", "optd": "4/5th of mean dimension", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following proportion of the ingredients of concrete mix, is not in conformation to arbitrary method of proportioning", "opta": "1 : 1 : 2", "optb": "1 : 2 : 4", "optc": "1 : 3 : 6", "optd": "1 : 2 : 8", "opte": "1 : 4 : 10", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The increased cohesiveness of concrete, makes it", "opta": "less liable to segregation", "optb": "more liable to segregation", "optc": "more liable to bleeding", "optd": "more liable for surface scaling in frosty weather", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ratio of the length to breadth of a wooden float, is", "opta": "4.5", "optb": "5.5", "optc": "6.5", "optd": "7.5", "opte": "8.5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To ensure constant moisture content in aggregates", "opta": "area of each aggregate pile should be large", "optb": "height of each aggregate pile should not exceed 1.50 m", "optc": "aggregate pile should be left for 24 hours before aggregates are used", "optd": "conical heaps of aggregates should be avoided to prevent moisture variation", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Workability improved by adding", "opta": "air-entraining agent", "optb": "foaming agent", "optc": "oily-agent", "optd": "aluminium compound", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The commonly used material in the manufacture of cement is", "opta": "sand stone", "optb": "slate", "optc": "lime stone", "optd": "graphite.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If 20 kg of coarse aggregate is sieved through 80 mm, 40 mm, 20 mm, 10 mm, 4.75 mm, 2.36 mm, 1.18 mm, 600 micron, 300 micron and 150 micron standard sieves and the weights retained are 0 kg, 2 kg, 8 kg, 6 kg, 4 kg respectively, the fineness modulus of the aggregate, is", "opta": "7.30", "optb": "7.35", "optc": "7.40", "optd": "7.45", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Curing a concrete for long period ensures better", "opta": "volume stability", "optb": "strength", "optc": "water resistance", "optd": "water tightness and durability", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the construction of cement concrete floor, the maximum permissible size of aggregate, is", "opta": "4 mm", "optb": "6 mm", "optc": "8 mm", "optd": "10 mm", "opte": "12 mm", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The process of proper and accurate measurement of concrete ingredients for uniformity of proportion, is known", "opta": "grading", "optb": "curing", "optc": "mixing", "optd": "batching", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "Insufficient quantity of water makes the concrete mix harsh", "optb": "Insufficient quantity of water makes the concrete unworkable", "optc": "Excess quantity of water makes the concrete segregated", "optd": "Excess quantity of water causes bleeding in concrete", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The preliminary test is repeated if the difference of compressive strength of three test specimens, exceeds", "opta": "5 kg/cm2", "optb": "8 kg/cm2", "optc": "10 kg/cm2", "optd": "12 kg/cm2", "opte": "15 kg/cm2", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct proportions of chemical ingredients of cement", "opta": "Lime : Silica : Alumina : Iron oxide : 63 : 22 : 6 : 3", "optb": "Silica : Lime : Alumina : Iron oxide : 63 : 22 : 6 : 3", "optc": "Alumina : Silica : Lime : Iron oxide : 63 : 22 : 6 : 3", "optd": "Iron oxide : Alumina : Silica : Lime : 63 : 22 : 6 : 3", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transport of concrete by pumps, is done for a distance of", "opta": "100 m", "optb": "200 m", "optc": "300 m", "optd": "400 m", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If X, Y and Z are the fineness modulli of coarse, fine and combined aggregates, the percentage (P) of fine aggregates to combined aggregates, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Slump test is done for", "opta": "clay", "optb": "sand", "optc": "lime", "optd": "concrete.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The high strength of rapid hardening cement at early stage, is due to its", "opta": "finer grinding", "optb": "burning at high temperature", "optc": "increased lime cement", "optd": "higher content of tricalcium.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The weight of ingredients of concrete mix, is taken in kilograms", "optb": "Water and aggregates are measured in litres", "optc": "The finished concrete is measured in cubic metres", "optd": "20 bags of cement make one tonne", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Concrete mainly consists of", "opta": "cement", "optb": "aggregates", "optc": "admixture", "optd": "water", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vicat's apparatus is used for", "opta": "fineness test", "optb": "consistency test", "optc": "setting time test", "optd": "soundness test", "opte": "compressive strength test.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "M 150 grade of concrete approximates", "opta": "1 : 3 : 6 mix", "optb": "1 : 1 :2 mix", "optc": "1 : 2 : 4 mix", "optd": "1 : 1.5 : 3 mix", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Workability of concrete is measured by", "opta": "Vicat apparatus test", "optb": "Slump test", "optc": "Minimum void method", "optd": "Talbot Richard test.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rock which is not calcareous, is :", "opta": "lime stone", "optb": "macl", "optc": "chalk", "optd": "laterite", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Internal friction between the ingredients of concrete, is decreased by using", "opta": "less water", "optb": "fine aggregates", "optc": "rich mix", "optd": "more water and coarse aggregates", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For road pavements, the cement generally used, is", "opta": "ordinary Portland cement", "optb": "rapid hardening cement", "optc": "low heat cement", "optd": "blast furnace slag cement", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Construction joints are generally provided in concrete", "opta": "roads", "optb": "retaining walls", "optc": "lining of canals", "optd": "lining of tunnels", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}